INTRODUCTION

Hi, I'm James. I'm an independent animator from the United Kingdom. I have experience in both professional studio environments in France, and producing my own successful animated content online. I'm well versed in the process of working closely with clients to form a deep mutual understanding of a project and bringing new ideas to the table. I have over 10+ years of experience with Adobe Flash and much experience with the Adobe Suite in general. I am very confident in my workflow, extremely hard working and passionate about animation.



JAMES CUNNINGHAM

Email:

glasscaked@gmail.com

Tele: 07871819119

Location: France / United Kingdom

EXPERIENCE

Studio Yotta, Telecommute, Portland, Oregon — Rough Animator

January 2020 - March 2020

Animated rough shots for a music video collaborating with the artist 'Yaeji'.

Studio Redfrog, In-house, Lille, France — Keyframer, Inbetweener

January 2019 - December 2019

Keyframe and inbetween a full episode of an animated television series named 'Sardine de l'Espace' on a weekly basis.

Game Grumps, Telecommute, Los Angeles, California — *Director, Animator, Audio Editor*

May 2016 - September 2016

Find an audio sample of my choosing, edit and master it, then direct and fully animate a short for the client.

VideoGameDunkey, Telecommute, United States — Director, *Animator*

July 2013- September 2013

Follow a basic script and audio sample then direct and animate a short film for the client.

GlassCake, Independent — Owner

July 2009 - August 2013

Ran a successful independent YouTube channel which I would regularly create animations for regularly garnering millions of impressions.

WEBSITE (DEMO REEL AND SAMPLES)

https://vimeo.com/glass cake

SKILLS

Adobe Flash (Draftsmanship, Traditional/ Puppet Animation)

Adobe After Effects (Animation/Motion Graphics)

Adobe Premiere (Video Editing)

Adobe Audition (Audio Editing)

TurboPunch Ltd, Telecommute, London — *Animator (Voluntary)*

July 2008 - August 2008

Co-created a short film named 'asdfmovie' that went on to receive over 60 million views.

LANGUAGES

English

EDUCATION

University for the Creative Arts, Farnham — BA (Hons) Animation Graduate

September 2014 - July 2017

Wilsthorpe Business and Enterprise College, Long Eaton ─ 5 GCSEs

September 2006 - July 2011

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Orange Trick — Short (Animated) Film

May 2015 - November 2015

Produced, Directed and Animated an independent comedy short film.

https://vimeo.com/396286650

Jared. — Short (Animated) Film

May 2015 - November 2015

Produced, Directed and Animated an independent comedy short film.

https://vimeo.com/181294849

The What If Introspective — Short (Animated) Film

January 2017 - May 2017

Produced, Directed and Animated an independent short film with an uncanny atmosphere.

https://vimeo.com/236426443

Animate a Grump Collab Segment— Animated Segment

February 2017 - March 2017

Directed and Animated a segment for a large collaboration with approximately 100 other animators.

Totally Tubular Collab Segment— Animated Segment

February 2018 - March 2018

Directed and Animated a segment for a large collaboration with approximately

250 other animators.

https://vimeo.com/289979042